<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science &amp; Visualisation Portfolio on Eamon Corr</title>
    <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science &amp; Visualisation Portfolio on Eamon Corr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Human Resources Attrition Prediction App</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>This machine learning application predicts which employees are more likely to stay or quit the business. Using models to predict if a staff member is likely to quit can support HR&amp;rsquo;s ability to be proactive and to take actions to prevent or at least minimise the probability of the employee leaving. Simply input some details and the app will make a prediction and it&amp;rsquo;s probability. This application is built with Python &amp;amp; deployed using streamlit and Heroku.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Machine Learning Project with Streamlit Deployment</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>Check out this machine learning interactive application that predicts the strength of concrete using different models. Choose from different Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) options, apply feature engineering, and tweak a few hyperparameters tuning options. Test the various models and determine their accuracy. This application is deployed using streamlit, a versatile interactive open source framework ideal for model exploration and machine learning applications.  
Interactive Machine Learning Project with Streamlit Deployment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Libraries for Visualisation</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>There are many python visualisation libraries available to plot scatter plots, bar charts, heatmaps and histograms. Some can be a little more sophisticated and interactive than others but it really comes down to what&amp;rsquo;s appropriate for the project and your visualisation requirements, i.e. a static chart may be suffice or maybe something more interactive is required. There are of course many other options, like Boheh, Pygal and Altair, to name just a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufacturing Quality Performance Interactive Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Manufacturing Quality Dashboard visualises manufacturing, supplier performance and customer satisfaction for a manufacturing facility. The Web Application is built using Python, Plotly and Dash libaries. The App pulls data from three different sources and visualizes the data in various interactive charts and tables.  
Dashboard Web Application
Link to GitHub Depository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShinyApp Titanic Survival Predictor</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Titanic Survival Predictor ShinyApp. Created using interactive web apps straight from R. Would you Survive the sinking of the Titanic? Simply enter a few details and the Shiny App will predict your probability of survival with a 94% Accuracy. Experiment with different scenarios and see if your chances improve or deteriorate.  
Titanic Survival Predictor ShinyApp
The full source code for this Shiny App can be found on my GitHub page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Australia Dive Site Locator</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Locate your local South Australian dive sites. Created using R Markdown and Leaflet. Click on a site for the dive site name and maximum depth.  
The full source code for this App can be found on my GitHub page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Rental Visualisation</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Count of bikes rented vs hour for working &amp;amp; non-working days. The Visualiation is built using R, R Markdown &amp;amp; Plotly. Check out how time of the day, temperature, and working/non-working days, impact bike usage.  
Link to GitHub Depository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict Exercise Performance</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>There are many devices that record key fitness performance metrics making it possible to collect a large amount of data about personal activity. Usually the goal is to measure regularly so to improve fitness, health and find new patterns in behaviour. One thing that people regularly do is quantify how much of a particular activity they do, but they rarely quantify how well they do it. This project will use data from accelerometers on the belt, forearm, arm, and dumbbell of 6 participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eamoned.github.io/EamonC_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>My Social Media platforms
   Platform URL     Twitter: https://twitter.com/Eamon_corr   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/eamoncorr/   GitHub: https://github.com/Eamoned    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
